# Ryan Foley

### **Fullstack Software Engineer**

519 Sargent Ct. Benicia, CA 94510 209-715-8154

ryfo720@gmail.com

https://github.com/ryfoa6

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryfoa6/

https://ryfo720-portfolio.herokuapp.com

## Summary

I am a Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for solving problems and challenging myself. I am open to improving and consistently look for better ways of delivering a superior customer experience to my clients.

My passion for Software Development started with building electronics and programming microcontrollers as a hobby but now I create full-stack applications. I create full stack applications. My spatial relation skills have helped me to become a finer engineer by lending me the ability to build mental models, which aids in solving complex problems, as I am able to manipulate and move data.

#### Skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Node.js, Express.js, Django

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

## **Projects**

Minesweeper | https://ryfoa6.github.io/Minesweeper

Created a Minesweeper game written in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

#### Magic The Gathering Deck Builder | https://ryfoa6-magic-the-gathering.herokuapp.com

Created a Magic The Gathering Deck Builder using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Bootstrap. The app made API fetch calls to <a href="https://api.scryfall.com">https://api.scryfall.com</a>, and displays Magic The Gathering cards filtered by color, card type and mana cost. After selecting the cards, users can then save the deck locally in the browser.

#### Play Me Chess | https://play-me-chess.herokuapp.com/

Create a chess game users can play with their friends online using JavaScript, DOM, and Socket.io so that users can create their own room to play their friends.

## **Experience**

Sign Designer & Installer || 10/2012 - 03/2020 California Color Graphics || Concord, CA

- Collaborated with customers to discuss their needs.
- Installed and maintained various signage.
- Created designs using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.

Sign Painter | 03/2003 - 08/2012 Bay City Roller | Concord, CA

- Actively listening to a customer's needs.
- Made sales calls to customers to maintain existing business relationships.

## **Education and Certificates**

General Assembly | Software Engineering Immersive | September 2020 - December 2020

Udemy | Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp | May 2020

Udemy | The Complete SQL Bootcamp 2020 | May 2020

Udemy | Complete Python Bootcamp | April 2020